<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comment on Dozenoaks Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/comment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comment on Dozenoaks Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/comment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sci twitter like a ‘pro&#39;</title>
      <link>/2017/11/sci-twitter-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/sci-twitter-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>The science twitter community can be a hugely beneficial resource, it can also be overwhelming if your new to it. I asked the scientists of twitter what platform they were using to interact with twitter itself (‘for a thing’). This post is not the thing I was eluding too, but the poll threw up a few tips I thought it worth drawing attention too and I figured I’d chuck some of my own tips in while I was at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pregnant/new mum guide to science conferences</title>
      <link>/2015/06/the-pregnant-new-mum-guide-to-science-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/the-pregnant-new-mum-guide-to-science-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy and new motherhood has brought a whole swathe of new experiences to my conference outings. This is my definitive guide to science conferences for the expecting/new Mum to help you decide where to expend your energy&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
      <link>/2014/12/merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description>When I was on the microscope imaging EB3 comets in axons as a control experiment for a control experiment, I got distracted by the comets in the dendrites - so pretty! They reminded me of the icicle lights on the outside of people&amp;rsquo;s houses you see this time of year. So this is my science Christmas card to you - have a Merry one :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>