<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sci Life on Dozenoaks Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/sci-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sci Life on Dozenoaks Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sci-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving the blog</title>
      <link>/2018/03/moving-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/moving-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog! Not just in terms of where it’s hosted, but how the whole thing is built. Previously I’d been using ghost, which was fine up until the moment I wanted to publish more code/analysis. The process of copy-pasting code and exporting images was taking more time than writing the code itself.
I’m now using the blogdown package which builds static websites within RStudio using Hugo and lets you publish the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sci twitter like a ‘pro&#39;</title>
      <link>/2017/11/sci-twitter-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/sci-twitter-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>The science twitter community can be a hugely beneficial resource, it can also be overwhelming if your new to it. I asked the scientists of twitter what platform they were using to interact with twitter itself (‘for a thing’). This post is not the thing I was eluding too, but the poll threw up a few tips I thought it worth drawing attention too and I figured I’d chuck some of my own tips in while I was at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pregnant/new mum guide to science conferences</title>
      <link>/2015/06/the-pregnant-new-mum-guide-to-science-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/the-pregnant-new-mum-guide-to-science-conferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy and new motherhood has brought a whole swathe of new experiences to my conference outings. This is my definitive guide to science conferences for the expecting/new Mum to help you decide where to expend your energy&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>